Hello everyone, I am Adam.
This topic is the way for programmers from junior to senior engineer
Lets talk about the 10 stages of career promotion
if you are a new beginner, I hope to help you. Now follow me!
No matter which IDE you are using, you must learn to use hot keys
Yes, On the one hand is to pretend to bring you pleasure.
On the other hand is to save time. You are a coder be professional.
Don't click the mouse poke around.
If it is Linux VIM or NANO full of keyboard operation, it is not so neat
Basically 'copy and paste delete and undo exit and save'
If you have learnt 'Operation by Line, Find and Replace', you will be better
For more operations, please refer to the pdf file at the bottom of the video
Hotkey Guide.
As the saying goes, workers must first sharpen their tools to do their best
A wrench is good for an engineer whole life
The same is true for software engineers
From development tool IDE to make your own tool
It takes a lot of time to save the toolbox
Juniors must at least know the common tool
There is also a lot of content about tools.
Chat later in the future
In the Java world
Google's Guava core library
Apache's Commons component
Spring's Utils framework
These tools can save a lot of cumbersome operations
For example, Guava's collection tool package
StringUtils Can solve the problem of string operation in the development process
BeanUtils Can quickly make entity copies
what? Never heard of it?
Colleagues need to change another welcome when they say hello tomorrow
Hi Bro! long time no see! Writing bugs aha?
Distributed version control system
Strictly It's not just a code management software
It is an idea A file backup idea
Let's revisit this from the example of protecting eggs
If you have a basket of eggs
How do you protect and eat it within the shelf life What issues do you need to care?
Is the basket strong and durable? If the basket is being broken What can I do?
Whether to carry the basket? Eat eggs at noon or at work at night?
Do I need to number the eggs?
If I take the eggs in the wrong order and eat them?
Do I need a camera on the basket to catch the eggs change?
......
May not take into account so many problems in life
But in the programing world Everything is data
Missing is missing
Do you remember your earliest camera phone,where are the photos you took？
Important information must be very careful:
Automatic multiple backup and Get it anytime, anywhere
Git, An automatic backup history、Collaboration and distribution、Anywhere、Code management software
Linus took it from his toolbox
The network drive you are using like Baidu Disk Google Disk OneDrive
Just like Git
The purpose is to manage your files (code)
Ensure that the usability, security, and coordination of files (code) are balanced in emergencies.
The earliest programming was procedural oriented programming
Later There was no hierarchical classification.
The Object Oriented Programming concept was popular.
I also pondered this concept for several days when I was junior.
I found out that procedural just want to tell you how to treat it the same way
Put things together
The purpose is to reuse and classify.
Later, JS moved from the front end to the back end.
The anonymous method and function closures popular again.
However,Thought is object-oriented and behavior is as process-oriented as possible
Don’t expose what can be hidden.
Life is short. Use closures.
Since I used SVN, I'm not afraid of jobs was too mach.
Since I use Git, I do not keep the garbage code anymore.
Be sure to delete the garbage code you commented out
Because you don't know the reason for commenting it after 30 days.
Once I pushed git, I deleted the deprecated code boldly.
My code submission contribution in the team
Deleted code were more than added code.
As an excellent coder
At work the skill requirements are not absolute
but Logic.
10-minute code may take 3 hours to debug.
Debugging is not just trial errors.
It is more about clarifying the ins and outs.
Remember that there are no bugs for no reason.
The technology field needs to be logically clear.
The business field needs this thing more.
Why do you want to do this business?
Why do you want to achieve this business?
You must ask more in your heart, Why?
Remember the tool classes mentioned above.
The tool classes were standard demonstration model for programmers.
From the junior to the senior
That is the process which from using other people's tools to developing tools.
做程序和做Just like a carpenter.
You can make the ergonomic business code your own.
Business code implementation must do everything possible to be pure
A pure component should solve a small problem.
The laziness here is not to let us do less work
Divide the work finer and finer
Become a code commander Lie down and finish your work
How to distinguish between programmers.
Plaid shirt jeans Black frame glasses backpack.
Of course, I won’t teach you how to beautify yourself.
Just to express the importance of OCD.
Tab replaces four spaces!
Never wrap the left curly bracket! !
The comments must be aligned with the code! ! !
Be sure to leave a line blank after a period of business processing! ! ! !
When you agree with me
As a senior coder, you must read the following tips
Learn to be generous and permit junior's mistakes
I have also followed the git commit record of teammates
I have also Silently open the code of the teammate and then close it
I have also optimized the writing method, revised the format and then rollback
Finally relieved, give up optimizing others' code
People have different tastes
Don't be too demanding on your teammates
let the junior make bold mistakes
and be happy with the junior
Be sure to allow elementary mistakes, premature optimization is the source of all evil
当你处在关键岗位上时
大大小小的会议是跑不掉了
morning meeting Evening meeting Summary meeting
Training meeting Demand meeting Technical seminar meeting
Demonstration meeting Docking meeting Demand communication meeting
At first you will feel that these meetings waste a lot of your working time
When you slowly realize it, you will find that this is the beginning
of your entry into the management post
Meetings can get you into business
Suddenly realized that he was a good product manager
At the same time, prepare a nice glass
It's better to put a little more water
Always forget to drink water when touching the keyboard
Take this opportunity to drink more water
In 1665, Newton went to the countryside to avoid the plague
Self-isolation No out-going No shopping
No party
He researched the principle of life and science
The COVID-19 Outbreak just gave us such an opportunity,
Being alone allows us to calm down and think more.
Don't just be a programmer
Do something important
Do something meaningful
Do something that solves the problem
You are the problem solver, creator, innovator
Not a programmer, programming is just a tool for you to complete innovation
To solve the actual problem
See you next time